尼基塔 快走
Oh, Nikita, just go.
不 油箱就要爆炸了
No! The tank's gonna blow!
我知道 我要你活着 快走吧 求你了
I know. I want you to live. Just go. Please.
我不走
I'm not going.
我爱你 该死的 快走
I love you! Damn it, just go!
我也爱你
I love you, too.
搜索"海德克"
海德格查的怎么样了
Where are we on Heidegger?
是海德克
Heidecker.
伯克霍夫 求你告诉我
Birkhoff, where are we on our best chance
迈克尔的手有多大可能复原
at fixing Michael's hand, please?
你以为我在这里干什么
What do you think I've been doing here?
我又在查看海德格
I've been going back over all
为"组织"提供的所有东西
the stuff Heidecker gave division.
夺命芯片 聚合物面具 药物
Kill chips, polymer masks, pharmaceuticals,
任何与间谍有关的东西
anything spy-fi.
有发现吗
And you found something?
没有
No.
但我记起了一件事
I remembered something.
海德克以前会来做跟进访问
Heidecker used to come in for follow-up visits.
他过来和医生们交流
He'd stop by, talk to the doctors,
收集他们记录的临床数据
pick up any clinical data they recorded.
这些人利用"组织"做进一步实体试验
These guys used division for advanced field testing.
珀西视我们为棋子
To Percy, we were pawns.
而海德克视我们为小白鼠
To Heidecker, we were lab rats.
所以我开始思考
And that made me wonder.
海德克现在的小白鼠是谁
Who are Heidecker's lab rats now?
见见科斯塔·波齐莱
Meet Kosta Beciraj.
他是科索沃的副总理
Deputy prime minister of Kosovo
也是海德克最新的实验对象之一
and one of Heidecker's newest test subjects.
表面上 科斯塔和其他政治家一样
On the surface, Kosta looks like any other politician,
但是深入发掘
but scratch the surface
就会发现一个复杂的犯罪轴心
and there's a chewy criminal center.
犯罪集团 毒品交易
Ties to organized crime, drug trade,
贩卖人口 无恶不作
human trafficking, you name it.
为什么这样的人会同意当别人的小白鼠
Why would a guy like this agree to be somebody's lab rat?
一年前 科斯塔秘密被送往医院
About a year ago, Kosta was secretly rushed to the hospital
做急诊手术
for emergency surgery.
官方说法是
The official story is,
他被宠物老虎咬成轻伤
he was receiving treatment for minor injuries
所以被送去医院接受治疗
after being attacked by his pet tiger.
他是007电影里的反派吗
Who is this guy, a Bond villain?
别激动 还有哦
Keep your shirt on, double oh hottie.
他让人杀了老虎
He had the tiger put down,
闭不出门
walled himself up inside his house.
他不想任何人知道真相
He didn't want anyone to know the truth.
其实并不是老虎
It wasn't a tiger.
而是中情局的人想杀他
The CIA tried to kill him.
他们失败了 但…
Now, they failed, but...
他失去了一条腿
He lost his leg.
经胫骨截肢
Transtibial amputation.
看看这个
Now, check this out.
这些照片是几周前拍的
These were taken just a few weeks ago.
怎么回事
What the hell?
他和魔鬼做了交易
Deal with the devil.
海德克
Heidecker.
科技间谍
Spyfi.
我们怎么抓住他
How do we get him?
我做了调查
Did some digging.
海德克大约一个月来一次科索沃
Heidecker's been visiting Kosovo about once a month.
他的第一站是科斯塔家
His first stop is Kosta's house.
我猜是给以假乱真的腿
My guess would be some kind of maintenance
做点维护
on the wonder leg.
没准还糟蹋几个黄花大闺女
That, and maybe the sacrifice of a virgin or two.
他待三天
He stays for three days
然后飞回不明之地
and then flies back out for parts unknown.
你知道他下次是什么时候来吗
Do we know when his next trip is?
他每个月一号过去
He flies in every month on the first.
就是今天
That's today.
我只有两天时间过去
I have two days to get there,
抓住海德克 然后带他回来吗
grab Heidecker, and bring him back?
你说"抓住"他是什么意思
What do you mean, "Grab" Him?
和我平常的意思一样
Same thing I usually mean.
"跟我来 我不会伤害你
"Come with me. I'm not gonna hurt you.
我们得走了"
We gotta go."
我把他带回来
So, I get him back here,
他告诉我们怎么给迈克尔装上新手
and he shows us how to give Michael a new hand.
你觉得瑞安会同意吗
You think Ryan's gonna okay that?
这不是"组织"行动 而是私事
This is not a division op. It's personal.
天知地知 你知我知
The only people who need to know are you, me, and...
还有迈克尔知道
Michael.
我得告诉他
I gotta tell him.
尼基塔
Nikita.
你和总统的会议如何
Hey, how'd your meeting with the President go?
我们安然地站在这儿 说明挺顺利的
We're still standing here, so I think it went fine.
又回到我和迈克尔刚在讨论的事
Which brings me to what Michael and I were discussing.
鉴于我在华盛顿时 他运筹帷幄
Given how well he ran ops while I was in D.C.,
我邀请他接下这份工作
I've asked him to assume that role permanently.
就跟珀西掌权时
Yeah, it's like the job I used to have
我的任务一样
when Percy was running the place.
只不过瑞安保证不会杀我
Only Ryan promised that he won't try and kill me,
还是有些区别
so that's a little different.
虽然提拔了你
Well, it's the least I could do
但是没加薪水 这样聊表心意吧
since the promotion doesn't come with a raise, huh?
没错
Right.
真是太好了 恭喜
That's great news. Congratulations.
谢谢
Thanks.
我得先过去了
I should probably get down there.
你是来找我还是瑞安的
Uh, did you need me or Ryan?
瑞安
Uh, Ryan.
好的
Okay.
他看上去好多了
He seems better.
你怎么样
How are you doing?
我还在调整
I'm still adjusting.
可能没他调整得那么快
Although not as fast as he is, I guess.
我知道这对你来说很困难
Look, I know this can't be easy on you.
我希望我能帮上忙
I wish there was something I could do to help.
事实上 我可能需要休息几天
Actually, I could use some time off.
我们需要确认那条腿是真的
We need to confirm that that leg is real.
这个仪器能检测出来 是吗
This'll do it, right?
让我们确认一下吧
Let's make sure.
看来你有些脑损伤
Why don't I use it to examine your head since you seem
可以试试用它检测一下你的脑子
to be suffering from some sort of brain damage?
我以前也单独行动过的 呆子
I've been on solo missions before, nerd.
你就不能找艾丽克斯 欧文
Can't you call Alex or Owen
或其他什么人给你支援
or someone? Just have some backup?
不行 欧文的肋骨还没有恢复好
No, Owen is still recovering from his broken ribs,
艾丽克斯和肖恩出城去了
and Alex has gone out of town with Sean,
去见家人之类的事情吧
some sort of meet-the-family thing.
我不能把她叫回来
I can't pull her away from that.
那迈克尔呢
What about Mikey?
你本来要去告诉他的 发生什么了
You were gonna tell him. What happened?
他升职了
He got a promotion.
他已经好多了
He's doing better.
他在自我调整
He...he's adjusting.
他早上甚至开了个玩笑
He even made a joke this morning.
好笑吗
Was it funny?
这些听上去都是好消息
Look, that all sounds like good news.
的确 他在重塑他的生活
It is. He's rebuilding his life.
所以如果我去告诉他 可以接上新的手
So, if I go in there and tell him about this new hand
但一切却落空了呢
and nothing comes of it?
发生了那么多事情
I can't give him false hope,
我不能再让他失望了
not after...everything.
这家伙接上了新的腿
Dude's got a new leg.
希望不会落空的
That hope is not false.
但危险却是真真切切的
Neither is the danger.
为什么你这么怕这个海德克
Why are you so afraid of this Heidecker guy?
他受雇于那些
He works for people who spend their days
整天想着用新奇有趣的方式杀人的人们
dreaming up new and interesting ways to commit murder.
死亡芯片 用牙齿做成子弹
Kill chips. Bullets made of teeth.
可以溶解胃的东西
That stuff that liquefies your stomach.
他们可不是善类 相信我
They're not nice folks. Trust me.
我可不怕一帮科学家
I am not afraid of a bunch of scientists.
他们很可怕
You should be.
伯克霍夫
Birkhoff,
他们有我需要的东西
they have something that I need.
如果他们是我修复迈克尔手的
If they are the only thing standing in the way
唯一绊脚石
of me and fixing Michael's hand,
他们才应该害怕
they are the ones who should be afraid.
普里什蒂纳 科索沃
尼基 根据中情局档案
Okay, Nikki... According to CIA files,
阁楼属于一个叫贝蒂娜·法斯的人
the penthouse is home to one Bettina Fath.
曾经是模特 现在是科斯塔·波齐莱的情人
Former model and current mistress of Kosta Beciraj.
谁啊
Yes?
送花的
Flowers.
放在桌上就行了
Just put it on the table, please.
没有卡片吗
No card?
没有小费吗
No tip?
科斯塔刚离开他的办公室
Kosta just left his office.
他在过来的路上了
He's on his way to you now.
我知道你很害怕 但我不是来伤害你的
I know you're scared, but I'm not here to hurt you.
你是来杀科斯塔的吗
You are here to kill Kosta?
我需要从他那得到些东西
I need something from him,
但是我不想杀了他
but I don't want to kill him.
为什么不杀他
Why not?
他就是个混蛋
He is a pig.
他不得好死
He deserves to die.
你有枪 为什么不杀了他
You have a gun. Why not shoot him?
我需要留着他的小命
Uh, well, I need him alive.
但是如果你能帮我 我也能帮你
But if you can help me, I can help you.
贝蒂娜 你在哪儿
Bettina, where are you?
你看上去好疲惫
You look tired.
你需要放松放松 让我伺候你吧
You need to relax and let me take care of you.
你想到了什么花样
So, what did you have in mind, huh?
一剂镇定剂
A sedative.
王八蛋
Pig.
机场有架飞机在等你
There's a ticket waiting for you at the airport.
你降落之后 去宾馆入住
When you land, check into the hotel.
那儿会有个包裹
There'll be a packet there,
你新人生所需的东西都在里面
everything you need to start your life over.
谢谢你
Thank you.
保持超声波稳定
Okay. Hold the ultrasound steady.
我需要精确的测量数据来计算
I need accurate measurements to calculate this.
我们可不想害死他
We don't want to kill him.
这真是活体组织
It really is live tissue.
内骨骼是金属的
Over a metal endoskeleton.
事实上 他的骨头好像是碳纤维的
Actually, it looks like his bones are made of carbon fiber.
有点失望啊
It's a little disappointing.
太棒了
It's awesome.
给他注射3毫升的NSM- 26
Okay, give him three ccs of the NSM-26.
这药多久才起作用
How long till this drug does its job?
他一醒来 就会觉得暖暖的有刺痛感
As soon as he wakes up, he'll feel warm and tingly.
然后就是肿痛
Then pain and swelling.
很快他就会叫海德克出诊
He'll be begging Heidecker for a house call before you know it.
我们在机场找到了贝蒂娜的车
We found Bettina's car at the airport.
她飞去柏林了
She flew to Berlin.
接着就不知所踪了
No idea where she went from there.
继续找
Keep looking.
她无权离开我 明白吗
She does not get to leave me, understand?
我的腿
My leg has, uh,
醒来后就一直隐隐作痛
it's been bothering me ever since I woke up.
海德克呢
Where is Heidecker?
司机已经去机场
Our driver is on his way to
给海德克送酬金了
meet Heidecker now to deliver the payment.
波齐莱先生给的酬金很慷慨
I find Mr. Beciraj's payment acceptable.
谢谢
Thank you.
准备起飞
All right, load the plane.
波齐莱先生要见你
Mr. Beciraj needs to see you.
不是吧 我们准备起飞了
Oh, no. We're about to take off.
我有其他计划 要准时飞去
I have a schedule that must be adhered to.
那你得迟到了
You will have to be late.
知道尼基塔上哪去了吗
Hey, do you know where Nikita went?
瑞安说她请了几天假
Ryan said she took a few days off.
不知道
Uh, I'm not sure.
可能跟艾丽克斯出门了吧
I think she went somewhere with Alex.
去做水疗还是什么的
Like a spa or something.
不是吧
Or maybe not.
你不是跟男朋友出城了
You're supposed to be out of town with your boyfriend.
抱歉揭穿你的谎话
Uh, sorry to expose your web of lies,
但他姐姐取消了见面
but his sister canceled.
她的孩子生病了
Her kids are sick.
再问你一次
Okay, let's try this again.
尼基塔在哪
Where's Nikita?
也许你该自己打电话问她
Look, maybe you should call her and ask her yourself.
别让我夹在中间难做人
I don't want to be in the middle of this.
这事你肯定有份参与
You're up to your neck in this.
不管是什么事
Whatever "this" is.
这都是什么
What is all this?
你做了什么
What did you do?
我重载了你的热键程序
I overrode your hotkey app
恢复了所有隐藏窗口
and restored all the hidden windows.
这上面的时间信息都是错的
The timestamps on these are wrong.
不 没有错
No, they're not.
肯定是错的
They have to be.
这家伙一年前失去了一条腿
If this guy lost his leg a year ago,
怎么还能到处走呢
he can't be walking around.
我只知道 这不是假肢
As far as we can tell, it's not a prosthetic.
是碳纤维做的骨头 但血肉都是真的
It's real flesh and blood grown over carbon fiber bone.
天哪 迈克尔
Oh, my God. Michael.
我的腿在抽痛
My leg is throbbing.
走路就会痛
It hurts to walk.
还肿起来了
There's swelling.
一定是那一针
It must be that shot.
怎么 也许是你给我注射的药物不对劲
What, you give me bad medicine, maybe?
药物没什么不妥
There is nothing wrong with the medication.
听起来像是被虫咬了 引发了过敏反应
This sounds like a bug bite, some kind of allergic reaction.
去找医生
Call a doctor.
我找了你
I called you.
你来搞定
You fix it.
我又不是医生
I'm not a doctor.
我的职责只是观察实验对象
My function is merely to observe
获取数据资料而已
and gather data from the test subjects.
我可不是你的小白鼠
I am not one of your lab rats.
我是吗
Or am I?
你的小实验完成了
Is your little experiment done?
你决定是时候弄死实验对象了
Have you decided it's time to put down the test subject?
没人要弄死你
No one is trying to kill you.
美国特工早就试过杀死我
American agents already try and kill me.
所以我才失去了一条腿
That's how I lost my leg.
也许他们又想来一次
Maybe they try again, hmm?
怎么 他们找过你
What, they get to you?
说服你玩阴的
Convince you to do the dirty work?
我可没时间听你说疯话
I don't have time to indulge your paranoia.
我的朋友
My friend.
你哪都别想去
You are not going anywhere.
伯克霍夫 出事了
Birkhoff, we have a problem.
科斯塔可能比我们想象的还要疯狂
I think Kosta may be crazier than we thought.
我得进去了
I gotta go in.
不 尼基塔 你快出来
No, Nikita, you need to get out.
- 迈克尔 你怎么… - 撤退
- Michael, what are you... - Pull out.
太危险了 你还孤身一人
It's too dangerous, and you're alone in there.
我不能让他们杀了海德克
I can't let them kill Heidecker.
可恶 尼基塔
Damn it. Nikita!
怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
你得先治好我的腿
You're going to fix my leg.
然后把我需要的药全都开给我
And you're going to give me all the wonder medicine
凡是能让它强壮健康的药都给我
I could ever need to make it strong and healthy.
在那之前 你哪儿都别想去
Until then, you will stay right here with me.
看到什么了
What?
你的枪让我很难集中注意力
The gun makes it very difficult
解决你的问题
for me to focus on your problem.
那干脆给你一枪 怎么样
Well, maybe I shoot you, huh?
一腿换一腿
A leg for a leg.
说不定你就能集中了
Maybe you'd focus then.
你可不想这会儿威胁我
Now, you don't want to threaten me.
为什么
And why is that?
快走
Come on, let's go.
找他吧
Looking for this?
科索沃
Kosovo?
你知不知道那儿的政治局势
Do you have any idea how delicate
有多微妙
the political situation is there?
你为什么不阻止她
Why the hell didn't you stop her?
你能告诉我上次
Please remind me of the last time
有人成功阻止尼基行动是什么时候吗
someone successfully stopped Nikki from doing anything...ever.
他没说错
He has a point.
现在我们面临着一场国际政治危机
And we have an international crisis.
尼基塔袭击了一国副总理
Nikita just assaulted the deputy prime minister
而且还是联合国成员国
of a U.N. Recognized...
科斯塔·波齐莱就是个罪犯
Kosta Beciraj is a criminal.
这一点大家都知道
Everyone knows that.
他同时也是一名正式的政府官员
He's a duly appointed government official.
这才是重点
That's what matters.
不 重点是她被俘虏了
No, what matters is, she's captured.
等等 等等 都闭嘴
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Shut up, everyone.
闭嘴 有尼基的信号
Shut up. I got Nikki.
她离通讯设备不远
She's close to her comm.
我会把你的头装在盒子里送给他们
I will send them your head in a box.
估计他们还能让你重新长出身体来
Maybe they can grow you a new body.
这是误会
This is a misunderstanding.
不 我为这条腿出了大价钱 而你出卖我
No! I paid you for this leg and you double-cross me?
现在该你付出代价了
Now it's you who will pay.
但得先把你造成的问题解决了
After you undo what you did to me.
我给你造成什么问题了
And what did I do to you, hmm?
你附加我的罪名一直都在变
Your accusations keep changing.
又是疯子科学家 又是CIA派来暗杀你的
Am I a mad scientist? Am I a CIA assassin?
你喜欢当独行侠
Oh, you travel alone
假装毫无畏惧
and pretend to feel no fear.
但她
But she...
她证明了那都是假象
she proves this is not so true.
好好看看当你保镖的下场
Pay close attention to what happens to your bodyguard.
这个过程对你来说 会更漫长
It will happen much more slowly to you.
你要动她 就别想我帮你
If you harm her, I won't help you.
他为什么要护着尼基塔
Why would he protect her?
想多争取点时间
He's buying some time.
你可能是感情丰富了点儿
Maybe you're warm-blooded after all.
也许她根本不只是你的保镖
She's maybe more than your bodyguard.
迈克尔 你不能毫无准备就去那儿
Michael, you can't go in there blind.
你们制定营救计划
You come up with the plan.
我到了给你们电话
I'll call you when I get there.
他的计划估计是 首先飞去科索沃
I gather his plan is, step one, fly to Kosovo,
然后大开杀戒吧
step two, kick ass?
我要跟他一起去
I want to go with him.
带上后援队
Take backup with you.
他每次出行都是你当影子武士吗
What, you shadow him every trip? Huh?
医生已经到了
The medic is here.
不在这儿 带去厨房
Not here. The kitchen.
把他们关到琪琪的房间去
Take them to Kiki's room.
等我收拾一下 再继续审问
We'll continue this after I'm cleaned up.
打给斯拉维萨
And call Slavisa.
告诉他 我要封锁边境
Tell him I want the borders closed.
副总理先生
Sir?
就说境内可能有其他叛国者
We may have other conspirators in the country.
他们一个都不能放过
They must not be allowed to escape.
告诉国防部长
Tell the minister of defense
通知各个检查站封锁边境 马上去
to radio the checkpoints and close the borders now!
这件事没法掩盖
There's no way we can keep a lid on this.
根本不可能阻止
No containment possible.
即使科索沃因此抓狂
Well, look, even if Kosovo flips out
封锁边境
and seals its borders,
也不能说明
it doesn't necessarily mean
"组织"与这件事有牵连
Division had something to do with it.
是不能 但如果被丹佛斯发现
Yes, but if Danforth finds out
再告诉总统
and tells the President,
我们就全都… 死路一条
then we are, all of us, dead.
他们会让尼基塔背上叛逃特工的罪名
They will brand Nikita as a rogue assassin
再毁掉这个地方以确保
and they will burn this place down to make sure
我们不会再次挑起类似的危机
we can't cause damage like this again.
我开始理解
I'm beginning to understand
珀西为什么要制作那些黑盒了
why Percy made the Black Boxes.
政府攥着你的把柄
Government has a trigger on you,
你可以其人之道还治其人这身
you put a trigger on them.
珀西
Percy.
珀西会如何应对这种情况呢
How would Percy deal with this kind of thing?
他会努力占据先机
He'd try to get ahead of it,
耍点手段
spin something.
他把这叫做"控制命脉"
He called it "controlling the narrative."
丹佛斯
Danforth.
长官 希望您不介意我
Commander, I hope you don't mind me
打你的安全专线
calling you on your secure line.
专线就是用来打的 弗莱彻 什么事
That's what it's for, Fletcher. What's wrong?
没什么
Uh, nothing wrong.
就是想知道目前科索沃国内的情况
Just curious about the situation in Kosovo.
什么情况
What situation?
埃文 别这样
Evan, please,
他们听到传言
They've heard the rumors.
我需要有确切消息回复他们
I just need to know what to tell them.
什么传言
Rumors about what?
科索沃准备封锁边境
That Kosovo is getting ready to close its borders.
如果真有这种事
If there was something going on,
但你没得到消息
But you haven't.
你想求证传言是吗 去问问TMZ[美国名人消息网]
You want to check rumors, call TMZ.
我可没那么多时间管这个
I don't have time for this.
等着他打回来吧
Now we just wait for him to call back.
怎么 我看起来像说谎吗
What? Did it sound like I was lying?
不是
No.
这就是琪琪的房间
So, this is Kiki's room?
他的宠物老虎 不过已经死了
His pet tiger. Now deceased.
我们还没正式认识一下
Well, we haven't been formally introduced.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我想知道刚才你为什么要救我
What I want to know is why you saved me back there.
出于令人羞愧的利己主义
Shameless self-interest.
波齐莱先生要杀了我
Mr. Beciraj is going to kill me.
你那一身的本领
Based on the skills you possess,
肯定是"组织"培养出来的
courtesy of your Division training,
我认为你是我保住性命的
I decided that you afforded me
最大筹码
the greatest chance of escape.
你怎么知道…
How do you know that...?
你怎么知道我的身份
How do you know who I am?
我认识"组织"里的所有特工
I know every agent in Division.
当然没交情 只是数据上的熟识
Not personally, of course. Statistically.
血型 体重 反应时间
Blood type, body mass, response time.
诸如此类的数据
Things of this nature.
没错
Right.
因为而你而言 我们都是有价值的工具
Because we were just useful tools to you.
希望这次也同样
I hope so. In this case.
当心点
Be careful.
兔子也是会咬人的
Some tools have a sharp edge.
你费尽千辛万苦来找我
Now, you went to a great deal of trouble to find me.
肯定是想从我身上得到些什么
I must have something that you need.
我一向遵循公平交易的原则
Well, I subscribe to the principle of fair exchange.
如果你帮了我 那我很乐意还你的人情
If you help me, i would be happy to return the favor.
只要你先说说要我做什么
Assuming you tell me what that favor might be.
我们有个同伴在战斗中受伤了
One of our own was wounded...in combat.
失去了右手
He lost his right hand.
天呐
Oh, dear.
你都能给他做一条新腿
You made him a new leg.
我想你也可以给我们做一只新手吧
I thought you could make us a new hand.
那条腿可不是我做的
Well, I didn't, uh, make the leg.
是我上头的人做的
The men I work for did.
我只是使用了那项技术
I merely applied the technology
时不时回来给它保养一下 收集下数据
and occasionally returned to service it, collect data.
跟我以前在"组织"做的工作一样
Same as I used to do at Division.
伯克霍夫说是你发明了这项技术
Birkhoff told me you were the source of the tech.
不不不 不是我发明的
No, no, not the source.
我只是发明者的销售代表
The, uh, sales rep for the source.
我看了那条腿 皮肤都是真的
I saw that leg. The skin was real.
没错 基本都是真的
It was real. Yeah, most of it is.
当然骨头是碳化纤维 不过组织嘛
The bone is carbon fiber, of course, but the tissue...
组织是利用他的DNA再生的
the tissue was regrown from his own DNA.
不可能
That's not possible.
你也见识过我们一些原版装置
You've worked with some of our prototypes.
我想你对"可能"的定义范畴
I would hope that your perspective on what's possible
也扩大了不少吧
might have been expanded by now.
夺命芯片这类装置没让我大开眼界
I'm sorry if gadgets like the kill chip
那可真是抱歉了
don't fill me with a sense of wonder.
我们开发这些不是用来杀人的
We didn't design them to kill.
是珀西选择将这种技术作这个用途的
That was simply how Percy chose to apply the technology.
用在别的地方
Used in other ways,
这些芯片可以帮助千千万万的人
those chips could help millions of people.
这样应用这种技术也是你首肯的
You allowed your technology to be used in this way.
你把它给了一个黑暗的机密组织
You gave it to a covert Black Ops group.
军队对科研的赞助
The military funding of science
使得技术产生了巨大突破
has led to breakthroughs
这种突破改变了
that have changed the lives
全球每一个个体的生活
of every single human being in the world.
你是说像原子弹一样
Ah, you mean like the atom bomb.
我说的是像原子能
I mean, like atomic energy.
像美国国防部高级研究计划局开发的互联网
Like the Internet, developed by DARPA.
海军发明的全球定位系统那样
Like GPS, developed by the Navy.
科学真是伟大
Yay, science.
答案是肯定的
The answer is yes.
我们能帮你朋友做一只新手
We can make your friend a new hand,
一只与他失去的几乎一模一样的手
one indistinguishable from the one he lost.
但在这个笼子里 可造不出来
But it can't be built from inside this cage.
那么你意下如何
So, what do you say we, uh,
把我弄出去呗
we get me out of here?
现在
Now...
老实交代 你把我的腿怎么了
Tell me what you did to my leg.
一种慢性毒素
It's a slow-acting poison.
现在你所经历的
What you're experiencing right now
只是个开始
is just the beginning.
明天 走路时会剧烈疼痛
By tomorrow, it'll be too painful to walk on,
到了下周 你就没命了
and by next week, you'll be dead.
给我解毒
You must fix it.
可以 但你得保证
We can, but we'll need some assurances.
我们救了你
If we help you,
你就得放我们走
you have to agree to let us go.
那你们给我什么保证呢
And what assurances do I have?
你们都已经给我下毒了
You already poisoned me once.
我怎么知道
How do I know
下一针会不会直接要我的命
that the next shot's not going to make things worse?
你可以先在你的手下身上试试
You can test it out on one of your many men.
如果他没死 你也不会有事
If he survives, you're safe.
你的腿一治好
And once your leg is healed,
就要送我们去指定的地点
you'll take us to a location of our choosing
我会把所有的抗排斥药物都给你
and I will give you all the anti-rejection medicine I have.
然后我们就会离开
We will leave.
你再也不会见到我们了
You'll never see us again.
我同意
I accept your terms.
解毒剂在哪里 在你包里吗
Where is the antidote? In your bag?
没有
No, I'm afraid not.
我们得在这里配置解毒剂
We'll have to manufacture the antidote right here.
要多久
And how long will it take?
几个小时吧
Several hours.
还有
And...
我们需要补给
We need supplies.
要的东西还真多
That's quite a list.
要凑齐这些东西可得花不少时间
It will take a while for my men to pull this all together.
让你的人抓紧时间
You better hurry.
谁都不希望 东西还没备齐
We wouldn't want that beautiful, perfect leg to rot
这条完美无缺的腿溃烂断掉
and fall off while they're out shopping.
我是弗莱彻
This is Fletcher.
关闭边防的事 你说对了
You were right about the borders.
很明智通知我 没人得到信息
Great call. No one else caught it.
总统有何打算
What's the President's plan?
先拖着
Stall.
直到我们想出对策
Until we figure out how to handle this.
去年科索沃警方试图接管北方岗位
You remember what happened last year
还记得发生了什么吗
when the Kosovo police tried to take over the northern posts.
长达六个月的暴力冲突
Six months of violence
双方边境都深受其害
on both sides of the border.
安理会应该不希望
I don't suppose the U.N. Security Council
那段历史悲剧再次重演吧
wants to repeat that particular part of history.
他们自己都手足无措
They aren't sure what to do.
总理是很通情达理的
The prime minister can be reasoned with.
可他身边的助手就难对付了
His right hand man is a different story.
所以中情局想要
It's why the CIA
第一个除掉他 是吗
tried to take him out in the first place, right?
他们应该不会再来第二次了吧
I don't suppose they could try again.
我不能再冒险搅黄中情局的任务了
I can't risk another botched CIA job.
如果把他干掉 就扫清障碍了
If we took him out, it would have to be clean.
没有人会发觉的
Invisible, even.
你该不会指的是…
You're not suggesting...
这才是建立组织的初衷
It's why Division was created, right?
你的人有办法接近波齐莱吗
Do you think your people can get to Beciraj?
应该有办法
I believe we might have a way in.
你不是说自己不是科学家吗
I thought you said you weren't a scientist.
对 我说过我不是那种
No, no, I said I wasn't the kind of a scientist
可以让肢体再生的科学家
who could engineer a way to regenerate someone's limb.
基本的化学实验 我还是能应付的
Basic chemistry, I can manage.
他的那条腿你是怎么弄的
So, the leg. Tell me how it works.
我只能和你解释最基础的原理
I can only explain it in the most rudimentary way.
好的
Good.
我也只能理解最基本的原理了
'Cause that's the only way I'll understand it.
好吧
All right.
人们都知道蝾螈和蜥蜴可以让断肢重生
We know that newts and salamanders can regrow severed limbs.
所以研究人员研制了一种化学混合物
So, the researchers developed a chemical cocktail
能产生多能干细胞
that creates pluripotent stem cells...
蜥蜴就是依靠那种东西让断肢再生的
the same thing salamanders use for regeneration.
那种东西要花多少钱呢
Do you know how much something like this costs?
不知道你有没有写备忘
I mean, I don't know if you got the memo,
组织已经失去了大部分政府资助
but Division lost most of its government funding.
我们的机构对金钱不感兴趣
Our organization isn't interested in money.
我们资金充足 我们最需要的是数据
We're very well funded. What we need is data.
来自临床试验和真人实验的数据
The kind that comes from clinical trials, real world testing.
你朋友的手是怎么断的
How did your friend lose his hand?
我是想了解一下
It would help me figure out
他能否成为再生工程的合适人选
if he's a good candidate for the regeneration process.
他被一辆着火的汽车压住了
He was pinned under a burning car.
不砍掉他的手 只能眼睁睁地看着他死
It was either cut off his hand or watch him die.
整齐的割伤
A clean cut.
不是挤压伤 不错不错
Not a crush injury. That's good, that's good.
当场就截肢了 是吗
I assume the amputation took place in the field, yes?
有大量失血吗
A great deal of blood loss?
流了好多好多血
There was a lot of blood.
非常非常多
Too much.
医疗救援队要一个小时才能到
Medical support was an hour away,
而且…
and, uh,
幸运的是 有把尖刀
Fortunately, there was a sharp blade
还有一辆燃烧的车
and a burning car,
所以烧灼伤口不是什么难事儿
So it only took a... a few tries to cauterize the wound.
对不起
I'm sorry.
那一切对你来说
It must have been very difficult for you to,
一定很不容易
uh, do what you did.
我觉得我永远都忘不了
I don't think I'll ever get the sound of his screams
他那撕心裂肺的叫喊声
out of my head.
当你看到他痊愈的时候
When you see him whole again,
一定会忘记的
you will.
我们已经进来了
Okay, we're at the compound.
你说要有一个计划
You told me to make a plan.
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
你得去杀死科斯塔·波齐莱
I need you to kill Kosta Beciraj.
这个指令是总统亲自下的
This order has been sanctioned by the President.
组织不是不再揽杀人的任务了吗
Hey, I thought Division didn't do kill missions anymore.
把这当做最后一次吧 祝你好运
Consider this the last one. Good luck.
我们已经就位
Okay, we're in position.
刚才在通信里监听到
From what we heard on the comm,
他们被关在琪琪的房间
they're holding them in Kiki's room.
在屋后的旧马棚里
It's behind the house in the old stables.
你们移动时
Once you start moving,
你们和房子之间没有任何遮掩物
there's no cover between you and the house.
好的
Okay.
比尔 你们在房子这一侧对付守卫
Bill, you guys keep the guards busy on this side of the house.
待克里斯搞定守卫后
And that'll be your position,
你们在那里就位
once Chris takes care of the guards.
冲 冲 冲
Go! Go, go, go!
是我们的人
This is our shot.
我们也准备好了 快把火枪放好
All right, we're good. Go ahead and use the fire.
命中火心
Fire in the hole.
我们走
Let's go.
迈克尔 你怎么来了
Michael? What are you doing?
科尔特斯模型
The keltrex prototype.
多谢 但还是叫我"迈克尔"吧
I prefer "Michael," but thanks.
- 计划是什么 - 把你带离这里
- What's the plan? - To get you out of here.
我在公路外一英里处有辆车
I've got a car half a mile up the road.
我们不可能走过去啊
We won't make it on foot.
我看见房子另一侧有一辆车
I saw another car on the other side of the house.
总部 我这儿有尼基塔和一个乘客
Ops, I've got Nikita and a passenger.
我们得换一辆交通工具了
We'll get another ride.
尽量让他分心 但不要杀死他
Keep him distracted, but don't kill him.
艾丽克丝 目标在房子南边
Alex, target is on the south side of the building.
长官 我们得撤了
Sir, we must go!
科斯塔
Kosta!
能登头条了吗
Cover story?
必须头条
Yeah, cover story.
目标歼灭
Ops, target is eliminated.
现场就像他们自己人误杀一样
It'll look like his own man shot him.
收到
Copy that.
A小队 撤离
Alpha team, disengage.
和艾丽克丝汇合 按计划准备收队
Rendezvous with Alex and follow exfil route as planned.
你抹掉安保视频监控了吗
Did you erase the security footage?
就像什么都没发生过一样
Like we were never there.
告诉总统任务完成
Tell the President it's done.
迈克尔 当地警察听到声音赶来了
Mikey, local fuzz got a call about all the noise.
他们来搅局了
They're coming to crash the party.
你们要远离主干道
You need to stay off the main roads.
好吧 艾丽克丝 带小队撤离
All right. Alex, take the team to the extraction point.
我们再找一条路 赶紧离开
We'll find another way. We gotta get going now.
- 我有架飞机 - 我们走
- I have a plane. - Let's go.
我是海德格
It's Heidecker.
我们在路上了
I'm on my way now.
准备好飞机
Please ready the plane
确保货物安全
and make sure the cargo is secure.
那模型太敏感了
Oh, yeah, that model always was twitchy.
我们在校准生物传感器时 出了点问题
We had trouble calibrating the biosensors.
我们最后发现
What we came to realize was that
由于信号穿越过多的传感器
the myoelectric feedback had been weakened
导致肌电反馈出现削减
because the signal was spread across too many sensors.
不好意思 太高深了
I'm sorry. You lost us.
西摩只需要持续发些反馈信息
All Seymour needs to do is clip a few of the returns.
你们会陆续地接到测试结果
You'll get far more consistent results, although
不过我觉得你没必要带着那假肢了
I doubt you'll be needing that prosthetic much longer.
你真觉得肢体再生技术能管用吗
Do you really think the limb regeneration's gonna work?
从你对他伤口的形容
Well, from what you tell me about his injury
以及我在这昏暗灯光中的观察来看
and from what I can see in this incredibly poor light,
我觉得迈克尔是个非常合适的人选
I believe Michael an excellent candidate.
我们到了 就在前面
We're here. Eh, just up ahead.
那个身着黑色夹克的绅士
Uh, that gentleman in the black jacket
是科斯塔最后一个保镖
is the last of Kosta's thugs.
在我飞机起飞前
We're going to have to deal with him
得先把他解决了 否则…
before my pilot can take off, otherwise...
知道了
Got it.
你们一定希望
Well, I'm sure you'll want to get started
越快开始手术越好
as soon as possible.
但我们还需要几次测试
We'll need to run a few tests.
你需要尽快开始抗排斥药物疗程
You're gonna want to start on the anti-rejection meds immediately.
迈克尔
Michael.
为什么飞机上有孩子
Why are there kids on the plane?
我叫你看好这些货物
I told you to secure the cargo.
就像我对尼基塔解释的那样
As I explained to Nikita,
每个人都要尽他们所能回报我
everyone pays what they can.
这些孩子是科斯塔给我的报酬
The children are Kosta's payment.
他们都是谁 是被绑架来的吗
Who are they? Were they kidnapped?
实话告诉你 我从来没问过
Well, to be honest with you, it never occurred to me to ask.
这一点关系也没有
It was irrelevant.
活体试验对我们的研究很重要
Real world testing is important to our research,
要找到条件合适的试验品是很难的
and it's very difficult to find able-bodied test subjects.
他们是孩子 不是试验品
They're children, not guinea pigs.
这些孩子都生活在极其贫困的地方
These children come from abject poverty.
他们的寿命本来就非常短
They have extremely short life expectancies.
至少现在他们的生命还有些意义
At least now, their lives will have some meaning.
难怪你会和珀西狼狈为奸
No wonder you and Percy got along.
你就是个禽兽
You're a monster.
而你是组织的特工
And you're Division agents.
你们都杀过无数人
You've both killed plenty of people.
你应该很熟悉这个世界的规则
You can't be surprised that this is how the world works.
但这不意味着我们会袖手旁观
It doesn't mean we're gonna stand by
让你恣意妄为
and let you get away with this.
尼基塔
Nikita.
总统对你们在科索沃的行动
The President was quite impressed
非常满意
by what you did in Kosovo.
说实话 我自己也是
To be honest, so was I.
我知道这种情况 对总统而言有些微妙
I know it was a delicate situation for the President.
把它伪装成政变未遂吗
Making it look like an attempted coup?
真是神来之笔
Stroke of genius.
不是我不重视这些荣誉
It's not that I don't appreciate the kudos,
但是这些话你完全可以直接在电话里说
but you could have said this all over the phone.
为什么你一定要见我
Why'd you need to see me?
我和总统认真斟酌了这件事
The President and I have given this matter a lot of thought.
我们想就组织的未来
We'd like to have a serious conversation
认真地探讨一下
about Division's future.
我就知道伯克霍夫在夸大其词
Well, I assumed Birkhoff was exaggerating, of course,
但你真的占了他的所有地儿
but you really did take over his whole space.
是的 我想把这些都排开
Yeah, I needed it to lay all of this out,
但这些是在飞机上找到的所有东西
but it's everything we found on that plane.
海德克没办法说话了
Heidecker can't talk,
但也许他的物品可以透露给我们一些讯息
but maybe his stuff can tell us something.
很抱歉搞砸了科索沃的那些事
I'm so sorry about Kosovo.
别道歉
Don't apologize.
我应该感谢你
I should thank you.
我本来已经准备好要放弃
I was ready to give up and accept that this
承认这是我达到的最好状态
was the best I was ever gonna have,
但你证明了 我是错的
but you proved me wrong.
你让我又燃起了希望
You gave me hope.
怎么可能 我打死了海德克
How? I shot Heidecker.
他死了 确实如此
He's dead. Yes.
但是他效力的那些人还在
But the people he works for aren't.
他们还活着
They're still out there.
他们可以解决 他们能给我一只新的手
They can fix this. They can give me a new hand.
迈克尔 那些都不是什么好人
Michael, these are not good people.
伯克霍夫警告过我 他是对的
Birkhoff was right to warn me about them.
你没理会他是对的
Yeah, and you were right to ignore him.
这是我重获所失的机会
This is my chance to get back what I lost.
我曾经连想都不敢想
I mean, I didn't even think it was possible.
但现在我知道这是可能的
Now that I know that it is,
我不能放弃
I can't give up on that.
我们不能相信他们
We can't trust them, and we certainly
更不能和他们做交易
shouldn't be in business with them.
我们不需要这样
We won't be.
我们去找到他们
We'll find them,
拿走我们所需要的
we'll take what we need,
然后销毁一切
and we'll burn their house down.
不计代价
Whatever it takes.
和总统女士谈得如何
How'd it go with the boss lady?
她对我们在科索沃的行动很满意
She was pleased with the operation in Kosovo.
也没人提要清算我们的财产
No one suggested liquidating our assets even once.
这是好消息 对吧
That's good news, right?
她还说了些什么
What else did she say?
她非常满意
She was so impressed
所以她让我们调查几件其它的案子
that she's asked us to look into a few other matters.
等等
All right, hold on.
我们都同意
We all agreed
以后不会再有任何政府任务
that there wouldn't be any government missions.
我们找到那些离开组织的特工
We'd find these rogue agents
然后把这地方关掉
and then we'd shut this place down.
非常清楚的清扫任务
Strictly clean-up duty,
并在短时间内完成
with a real hard expiration date.
我们要做什么
What do we do?
我觉得我们已经做得够多了
I mean, I feel like I've done enough.
这是四份文档
It's four files.
我们解决了他们
We take care of them,
也许一切就结束了
maybe that's the end of it.
不 这不是结束
No, not the end.
这只是个开始
This is how it begins.
如需其它字幕 请登陆新浪微博（WEB蓝光版美剧专业户）或发邮件
lj20090303@163.com